<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>IPython Books</title><link href="http://ipython-books.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://ipython-books.github.io/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://ipython-books.github.io/</id><updated>2014-09-26T00:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>IPython Cookbook released</title><link href="http://ipython-books.github.io/ipython-cookbook-released/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-09-26T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Cyrille Rossant</name></author><id>tag:ipython-books.github.io,2014-09-26:ipython-cookbook-released/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My new book, &lt;a href="/cookbook/"&gt;IPython Interactive Computing and Visualization Cookbook&lt;/a&gt;, has just been released! A sequel to my previous &lt;a href="http://ipython.rossant.net"&gt;beginner-level book on Python for data analysis&lt;/a&gt;, this new 500-page book is a &lt;strong&gt;complete advanced-level guide to Python for data science&lt;/strong&gt;. The 100+ recipes cover not only interactive and high-performance computing topics, but also data science methods in statistics, data mining, machine learning, signal processing, image processing, network analysis, and mathematical modeling.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Here is a glimpse of the topics addressed in this book: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IPython notebook, &lt;strong&gt;interactive widgets&lt;/strong&gt; in IPython 2+&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Best practices in interactive computing: version control, workflows with IPython, testing, debugging, continuous integration...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data analysis with pandas, NumPy/SciPy, and matplotlib&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced data visualization with &lt;strong&gt;seaborn, Bokeh, mpld3, d3.js, Vispy&lt;/strong&gt;...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Code profiling and optimization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High-performance computing with &lt;strong&gt;Numba, Cython, GPGPU with CUDA/OpenCL, MPI, HDF5, Julia&lt;/strong&gt;...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Statistical data analysis with &lt;strong&gt;SciPy, PyMC, R&lt;/strong&gt;...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Machine learning with &lt;strong&gt;scikit-learn&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Signal processing with SciPy, image processing with &lt;strong&gt;scikit-image&lt;/strong&gt; and OpenCV&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analysis of graphs and social networks with &lt;strong&gt;NetworkX&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Geographic Information Systems in Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mathematical modeling: dynamical systems, symbolic mathematics with &lt;strong&gt;SymPy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the code is freely available as IPython notebooks on the &lt;a href="https://github.com/ipython-books/cookbook-code"&gt;book's GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;. This repository is also the place where you can signal errata or propose improvements to any part of the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book uses Python 3, although most of the code will work fine on Python 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll find the book on &lt;a href="https://www.packtpub.com/big-data-and-business-intelligence/ipython-interactive-computing-and-visualization-cookbook"&gt;Packt's website&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/IPython-Interactive-Computing-Visualization-Cookbook/dp/1783284811/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1410688253&amp;amp;sr=1-1"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, and many other bookstores.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="python"></category></entry><entry><title>IPython Minibook released</title><link href="http://ipython-books.github.io/ipython-minibook-released/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-04-27T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Cyrille Rossant</name></author><id>tag:ipython-books.github.io,2013-04-27:ipython-minibook-released/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm glad to present my new book, &lt;a href="/minibook/"&gt;Learning IPython for Interactive Computing and Data Visualization&lt;/a&gt;, Packt
Publishing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book is a &lt;strong&gt;beginner-level introduction to IPython&lt;/strong&gt; for
interactive Python programming, high-performance numerical computing,
and data visualization. It assumes nothing more than familiarity with
Python. It targets developers, students, teachers, hobbyists who know
Python a bit, and who want to learn IPython for the extended console,
the Notebook, and for more advanced scientific applications.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The book first introduces IPython for interactive Python and shell
programming. It shows how IPython can considerably improve the
productivity of a developer who creates, debugs, benchmarks and profiles
Python code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, the reader learns the very basics of vector computing, and
discovers how to load and analyze numerical and tabular data with NumPy
and Pandas. The book shows the interactive visualization capabilities of
the platform with Matplotlib, SciPy and PIL. It also contains a few
image processing examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some techniques to accelerate Python code are also demonstrated, using
either interactive parallel computing features from IPython (using MPI
or not), or Cython to compile a portion of the code in C for really
interesting speedups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the book shows how IPython can be customized for advanced uses,
notably with the creation of new extensions and magic commands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The code is stored in a &lt;a href="https://github.com/rossant/ipython-minibook"&gt;GitHub
repository&lt;/a&gt;. It contains
IPython notebooks with most examples from the book.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>